The future begins.
Star Trek is a science fiction, action, adventure film directed by J.J. Abrams.
The fate of the galaxy rests in the hands of bitter rivals.
One, James Kirk, is a delinquent, thrill-seeking Iowa farm boy.
The other, Spock, a Vulcan, was raised in a
logic-based society that rejects all emotion.
As fiery instinct clashes with calm reason, their unlikely but powerful partnership is the only thing capable
of leading their crew through unimaginable danger, boldly going where no one has gone before.
The human adventure has begun again.
Cadet James T. Kirk, played by Chris Pine.
Commander Spock, played by Zachary Quinto.
Ambassador Spock, played by Leonard Nimoy.
Captain Nero, played by Eric Bana.
Captain Christopher Pike, played by Bruce Greenwood.
Dr. Leonard 'Bones' McCoy, played by Karl Urban.
Star Trek is a 2009 American science fiction action film directed by J.
Abrams, and written by Roberto Orci and Alex Kurtzman.
It is the 11th film in the Star Trek franchise, and is also a reboot that features the main characters of the
original Star Trek television series portrayed by a new cast, as the first in the rebooted film series.
The film follows James T.
Kirk (Chris Pine) and Spock (Zachary Quinto) aboard the USS Enterprise as they combat Nero (Eric
Bana), a Romulan from their future who threatens the United Federation of Planets.
The story takes place in an alternate reality that features
both an alternate birth location for James T.
Kirk and further alterations in history stemming from the time travel of
both Nero and the original series Spock (Leonard Nimoy).
The alternate reality was created in an attempt to free the film and the franchise from
established continuity constraints while simultaneously preserving original story elements.
The idea for a prequel film which would follow the Star Trek characters during their time in
Starfleet Academy was first discussed by series creator Gene Roddenberry in 1968.
The concept resurfaced in the late 1980s, when it was postulated by Harve Bennett as a possible plotline for what would
become Star Trek VI: The Undiscovered Country, but it was rejected in favor of other projects by Roddenberry.
Following the critical and commercial failure of Star Trek: Nemesis and the cancellation of Star Trek: Enterprise, the franchise's executive producer Rick
Berman and screenwriter Erik Jendresen wrote an unproduced film titled Star Trek: The Beginning, which would take place after Enterprise.
After the separation of Viacom and CBS Corporation in 2005, former Paramount Pictures president
Gail Berman convinced CBS to allow Paramount to produce a new film in the franchise.
Orci and Kurtzman were soon approached to write the film,
and Abrams was approached to direct it.
Kurtzman and Orci used inspiration from novels and graduate
school dissertations, as well as the series itself.
Principal photography occurred between November 2007 and March
2008, in locations around California and Utah.
Abrams wanted to avoid using greenscreen, and
preferred sets and locations instead.
Heavy secrecy surrounded the film's production and was under
the fake working title Corporate Headquarters.
Industrial Light & Magic used digital ships for the film, as opposed to
miniatures used in most of the previous films in the franchise.
Production for the film concluded by the end of 2008.
Star Trek was heavily promoted in the months preceding its release; pre-release screenings for the
film premiered in select cities around the world, including Austin, Sydney, and Calgary.
It was released in the United States on May 8, 2009, to critical acclaim.
The film was a financial success, grossing over $385.7 million
worldwide against its $150 million production budget.
It was nominated for several awards, including four at the 82nd Academy Awards,
winning Best Makeup—the only Academy Award a Star Trek film has won.
It was followed by the sequels Star Trek Into Darkness
(2013) and Star Trek Beyond (2016).
The film explores themes of spacecraft, teleportation, san
francisco, california, time travel, space mission.
The tone is thought_provoking.